Jon Urry

5 Glenville Road, Kingston upon Thames, Surrey, KT2 6DD













07986 371 299

jon@urry.me

ionurry

jon.urry.me

github.com/jon urry linkedin.com/in/jonurry

Profile

A customer-focused, technically proficient, software developer with 21+ years of commercial software development experience. Currently learning how to develop web applications using open source technologies. I'm looking for a job as a Junior Web Developer and expect to quickly progress from there.

Designed and implemented software used by: *BP, ExxonMobil, General Motors, Ford, Hyundai, Kia, Peugeot, Citroën, Chrysler, LG, Jaguar, Land Rover, Bentley, Aston Martin, US Air Force and multiple airlines including Lufthansa, Cathay Pacific, Air China and Alitalia.*

Skillset

Programming: HTML, CSS, SASS, JavaScript, ES6, XML, Node, Jest, SEO, Analytics, WordPress, C#, C, C++, Visual Basic, VB6, .Net, ASP.Net MVC, WPF.

Tools: UX, Responsive Design, Design Patterns, Unit Testing, Git, Chrome Inspector, Atom, VS Code, CodeKit, ESLint, Babel, Prettier, Slack, Assembla, UML.

Process: Agile Methodologies, Scrum, Test-driven Development.

Database: SQL Server, SSRS, SSIS, MySQL, Oracle PL/SQL, Performance Optimisation. **Management:** Pragmatic, Organised, Lead teams globally, Bonus/performance targets.

Recommendations

+ 19 more on LinkedIn

"He's a natural problem solver and is able to take on and successfully deliver some of the most challenging engagements out there. If you're looking for someone to hit the ground running, deliver to budget and timescales, I can't recommend Jon enough."

Jason Spencer

Director, Financial Advisory, Deloitte

"Jon is an outstanding software developer who led the development of the most important product in our portfolio..."

Dimitris Lyras

Managing Director, Ulysses Systems

"He has exceptional analytical skills and could always be trusted to find elegant and creative solutions when presented with complex technical problems. I have no hesitation in thoroughly recommending him."

Stuart May

Director, Product Management, Expedia.com

"Jon can define and create business technology solutions that will deliver competitive advantage."

Andor Miles-Board, Marketing & Business Development Manager, NextGen Technology

Achievements

- Designed web app and implemented database for Bluetooth interoperability testing that helped attract new customers more than doubling annual revenue to £2 million.
- Successfully led and managed a distributed team of software engineers in London, Mumbai and Chandigarh, delivering features on schedule and at a significantly reduced cost.
- Solved challenging and complex business problems. E.g. Interoperability of software versions. Others had abandoned this problem in the past only for me to succeed.

Jon Urry Page 1 of 2

- Designed and implemented dozens of SQL Server reports to deliver business critical information on demand saving many hours of work every week across the company.
- Designed and implemented an audit solution that enabled process inefficiencies to be highlighted and provided real metrics for accurate customer quotes.
- Implemented many optimisations to dramatically increase software performance. E.g. improving complex filtering process from 100 minutes to less than 10 seconds.
- Realised fully automated build tool. Significantly reduced labour costs (converting a 2-day manual task to a 1-hour automated task) and improved quality by reducing human error.
- Helped to turn around failing software project to automatically test in-car system interoperability.

Experience

IT Contractor, Agile Web Limited

2009 - 2017

Providing business critical software solutions to a Bluetooth interoperability testing company.

- Responsible for architecting, designing, developing and delivering software solutions to bring commercial savings and competitive advantage to clients.
- Creating XML generator for Ford Motor Company to power their global customer facing websites.

Product Manager, Ulysses Systems

2006 - 2009

Ulysses Systems is an award-winning provider of enterprise business intelligence software to the marine industry. Customers included: BP, ExxonMobil, Bourbon, Exmar and V.Ships.

- Responsible for 'Core Technologies' platform. Split 70% design/coding and 30% management.
- Promoted agile methodologies and helped define new and improved processes.

Team Leader, Ulysses Systems

2000 - 2006

- Led a team of software engineers who envisioned, designed and implemented a multi-user document management system from scratch.
- Designed and developed a UI framework. Reusable solution saved many weeks of development work and gave product a consistent look and operation.

Senior Software Engineer, Ulysses Systems

1999 - 2000

Improving legacy software for the marine industry.

Software Engineer, Integrated Sales Systems (ISS)

1999

CRM software for the healthcare, pharmaceutical and insurance sectors. Company acquired by Vodafone.

Analyst Programmer, TRO Learning (UK)

1996 - 1999

World-leading computer-based training (CBT) software company supplying aerospace training solutions to commercial and military organisations. Company acquired by The Vega Group.

• Designed, implemented and tested CBT applications, incl. \$250k flight simulator for US Air Force.

Education

1995	University of Huddersfield	MSc Scientific Computing
1994	University of Hull	Postgraduate Diploma Software Technology
1991	Imperial College of Science,	BSc Physics. Associate Royal College of Science.
	Technology and Medicine, London	Cycling Club Captain.

Jon Urry Page 2 of 2